三  二  一
Three, two, one.
你还想玩什么
What do you want to do next?
荡秋千怎么样
Uh, swings?
好吧  爬管呢
Okay. Um, crawl tube?
不玩
Nah.
不玩吗
Nah?
我想就这几个项目了  亲爱的
Well, I think we're running out of options, honey.
我想玩旋转木马
I want to go on the merry-go-round.
旋...  还玩这个啊
The m-- again?
但这回我一个人玩
But this time all by myself.
这不好办  小甜豆
I don't know, jellybean.
爸爸  我都六岁了
Daddy, I'm six.
又不是三岁小孩
I'm not a baby anymore.
求你了
Please?
-准备好了吗  -嗯
- You ready? - Uh-huh.
好吧
All right.
过来
Come here.
我来拿小熊
I'll take beary.
你答应我不告诉妈妈  好吗
Now you promise you're not gonna tell mommy, right?
要是被她知道了  我就死定了
She'll kick my butt if she finds out.
拉钩钩
Pinky swear.
好  去吧
All right. Go get 'em.
-记得要抓紧啊  -知道了
- Remember to hold on tight. - I will.
停下
Stop the ride!
艾米丽
Emily!
艾米丽  你在哪
Emily, where are you?
小艾
Em?
艾米丽
Emily?
艾米丽  你在哪  亲爱的
Emily, where are you, honey?
小艾
Oh, Em.
艾米丽
Emily.
亲爱的
Honey?
救命啊
Help me!
总监：
zlean
那一坨是不是咱们宝贵的肿瘤
Is that our precious little bundle of tumor?
它们长得真快  对吧
They grow up so fast, don't they?
你怎么知道我在这
How did you know I was here?
你说呢
How do you think?
福曼说的
Foreman.
也是啊  问他就简单多了
Actually, that would have been easier.
不是  我跟踪你来的
No, I followed you.
你难道没发现
It didn't occur to you that that might mean
我不想你来搅和我的癌症治疗吗
I don't want you involved in my cancer treatment?
我不是以医生的身份来的
I'm not here as a doctor.
我是来给你当支柱  给你打气的
I'm here as a towering pillar of strength.
去停车场当支柱去
Be a pillar in the parking lot.
不
No.
有多少次我告诉你
How many times have I told you
我不想你来烦我  但你就是不放过我
I wanted to be alone and you've made yourself a pain in the ass?
我欠你的
I owe you.
我说到做到  不是虚言
My word, not a word.
我能预感到我会后悔的
Realizing I'm most likely going to regret this,
但好吧
all right.
你干什么呢
What--what are you doing?
我的挚友得了癌症
My best friend has cancer.
放我一马吧
Cut me some slack.
还有  正当春假
Also, spring break.
我正度假呢
I'm on vacation.
但看看你  我敢说你在湿T恤比赛中
Although looking at you now, I can tell the wet t-shirt contest
肯定会输
is probably gonna suck.
豪斯休假
House taking time off
可是个不祥的预兆
is a bad sign.
"不祥的预兆"
"A bad sign."
就因为豪斯想陪陪威尔森
You think the apocalypse is coming
你就认为世界末日要到了吗
because House wants to be there for Wilson?
对
Yes.
你还嫩
You're new.
有个病例
We got a case.
六岁鼻出血患儿
Six-year-old with a nosebleed
伴呼吸困难
and breathing problems.
她天生有一种罕见的
She was born with
毛细血管扩张性共济失调基因突变[AT]
a rare mutation of A-T.
艾米丽在其一对ATM等位基因上
Emily has a unique variant
均有一罕见的变异
on both of her ATM genes.
其表现类似AT
Her disorder mimics A-T,
但未表现出所有症状
but not all of the symptoms.
这位是伊丽莎白·劳森医生
This is Dr. Elizabeth Lawson.
是约翰·霍普金斯医院的发育遗传学家
She's a developmental geneticist
对这个女孩的状况了如指掌
attached to JHU and an expert on the girl's condition.
伊丽莎白·劳森
Elizabeth Lawson.
艾米丽·劳森
Emily Lawson.
我是以医生的身份来的  不是一个母亲
I'm here as a doctor, not a mother.
鼻出血及气促是毛细血管扩张性
Nosebleeds and breathing problems are common symptoms
共济失调综合征的常见症状
of ataxia telangiectasia.
可能我们看到的就是
We could just be seeing
-这一疾病的自然演进  -不是
- the natural progression-- - It's not.
AT患者的预期寿命为二十年
A-T patients have a life expectancy of 20 years.
艾米丽才六岁  肯定是别的原因
Emily is only six. It's something else.
两天前我检查过她的双肺
I examined her lungs two days ago.
功能正常
They're functioning normally.
她从旋转木马上掉了下来
It says she fell off a carousel.
-颅脑外伤  -如果这么简单
- Head trauma-- - If the diagnosis was easy,
我就不用找你们了
I wouldn't need you people.
艾瑞克说你们是最棒的  所以我才来的
I'm here because, according to Eric,you're the best.
的确
We are.
你有没有想过韦格纳肉芽肿
Have you considered wegener's granulomatosis?
挺符合症状的
It's a good fit.
但她不能做X光检查
But she can't have X-rays.
AT导致她对电离辐射高敏
A-T makes her hypersensitive to ionizing radiation.
我给她做次核磁共振吧
I'll get her prepped for an MRI.
她比你们任何人
She knows more about her daughter's
都更清楚她女儿的遗传病
genetic condition than any of you.
她会很有帮助的
She'll be an asset.
或者不会
Or she won't,
艾瑞克
Eric.
这不是请求
This isn't a request.
用她吧
Use her.
肿瘤已向周边组织扩散
The tumor's spread to the surrounding tissue.
在手术切除前
We're gonna have to shrink it
我们得先将肿块缩小
before we remove it surgically.
我对你准备怎么做
I'm more interested in exactly
更感兴趣  迈克
how you plan to do that, Mike.
先进行保守治疗
We start conservative.
每日放疗  连续三周
Daily radiation treatments for three weeks.
之后如果缩小得不够
And, if it doesn't shrink enough after that,
我们会再进行化疗
we'll add the chemo--
如果之后缩小得再不够  我就死了
And, if it hasn't shrunk enough after that, I'm dead.
有超过七成半的机会
Look, you have over a 75% chance
单行放疗即可达到缩小目的
that the radiation alone is enough.
放松点
Relax.
来得急
Caught this in time.
在肿瘤侵及胸腺周围组织前
Catching it in time would have been
这么治疗还来得急
before it invaded the tissue around my thymus.
我要同期进行放化疗
I want the radiation and the chemo concurrently.
不必要地损伤免疫系统  何必呢
Why stress your immune system unnecessarily?
按我的方案来吧
Let's just go with my plan, okay?
-先放疗...  -我要询问其他医生的意见
- The radiation first...  - I'm gonna get a second opinion.
你是认真的吗
Are you serious?
你不也多次向其他病人建议
Look, I've seen you recommend this exact treatment
-这种治疗方案吗  -不要再说了
- dozens of times.  - We're done here.
我要找个真正有种的医生
I'll look for a doctor with some actual balls.
和你的朋友谈谈吧
Hey, you need to talk to your friend.
他这是让自己难堪
He's embarrassing himself.
作为一名医生  要更从容地
A doctor should be able to handle his own illness
面对自己的病
with a little bit more dignity.
我同意威尔森的说法
I agree with Wilson.
我的治疗方案没问题
My recommended treatment is sound.
我是说我同意你没种
No, I meant about the ball-less part.
办公室把你暴露了
Explains the office.
旋转木马而已
It was a merry-go-round.
丽莎  她还是个孩子  我们玩得很开心
She's a kid, Liz. We were having fun.
你也应该不时陪她玩玩
You should try it sometime.
开心  不像你  她才六岁
Fun? She's six, not you.
你知道她有平衡障碍的
You know she has balance issues.
我知道她...
I know that she's...
这是艾米丽的父亲  西蒙
This is Emily's father, Simon.
发病时是他陪着她
He was with her when the symptoms occurred.
她在我那一个礼拜了  她很好
I had her all week. She was fine.
我们可以一会再来
We could come back.
不用  患者已经准备好了
No need. Patient's ready for transport.
醒醒  小懒虫
Wake up, sleepy head.
我在商店看到这个
I saw it in the gift shop.
我知道你很喜欢它
I know how much you like them.
谢谢
Thanks.
医生带你去做磁共振
They're gonna take you for an MRI now.
就是"魔术般神奇的照片"
It means "Magic really cool images."
那不是"磁共振成像"的缩写吗
I thought it stood for "Magnetic resonance imaging."
我们到医院是家常便饭了
We've spent a lot of time in hospitals.
B行第九个格
B-9.
中了  我恨你
Hit. And I hate you.
不玩了
I'm done.
我把你的战船灭了吗
I sunk your battleship?
没有  但是我想吐
No. But I think I'm gonna puke.
很好  既然你喝得差不多高了
Good. Now that you're sufficiently buzzed,
就说说对近藤发飙的真实原因吧
what was the reason behind you freaking out on Kondo?
你害怕了
Are you scared?
拒绝接受事实
Are you in denial?
当别人说你有问题时
I know you get confused
对自己产生怀疑  我可以理解
any time someone thinks that you're wrong,
但我作为病人提出质疑
but it's not considered freaking out
就说我是发飙  也太过了吧
for a patient to ask for a second opinion.
好吧  这就是原因
Okay, well, here it is.
近藤说对了
Kondo is right.
你必须马上接受放疗
You should be in radiology right now.
不错嘛
Well done.
你憋了差不多两个小时才说这话
You've kept your word for almost two hours.
每多等一天
Every day you wait,
你胸腔里的小瘤瘤就更大一点
our pal toomie is growing larger in your chest.
你要是不想死
If you want to live,
别纠结了  果断采取措施
stop screwing around and do something about it.
好主意
Good idea.
我想
I think...
就从一个人过春假开始吧
I'll start with spending spring break on my own.
艾米丽  感觉怎么样
How you feeling in there, Emily?
还好吧
Good, I guess.
哪里不舒服吗
Is something wrong?
刚才我在装睡
I was only pretending to be asleep.
我是个不诚实的宝宝吗
You think that's dishonest?
这...
That's...
我女儿也经常这样
My daughters do that too.
要知道有的时候
But they know that sometimes,
爸爸妈妈看起来像是在吵架
when it seems like mommy and daddy are fighting,
实际上不过是他们担心你罢了
it's really only because they're worried about you.
你的妻子也想离婚吗
And does your wife ever want a divorce?
没有  家里一切都好
No. Everything's fine at home.
现在开始不要动  不要讲话
Hold still now. No more talking.
你怎么看她妈妈的
What do you think of her mother?
叫自己的女儿"患者"
She called her daughter "the patient".
如果我的孩子得了绝症
If my kids were born with an expiration date,
我也不知道...
I don't...
哪里疼
Where does it hurt?
我要爸爸  爸爸在哪
I want my daddy. Where's my daddy?
在导致永久性损伤前
We were able to restore circulation
我们恢复了她手脚的末梢循环
to her hands and feet before any permanent damage set in.
是原发性雷诺综合征吗
Primary raynaud's?
可能由磁共振室的低温诱发
The cold inside the MRI room could have set it off.
幽闭恐惧的应激也可使其加重
Stress can also precipitate the condition.
她对寒冷并不敏感
She's shown no evidence of cold sensitivity,
做磁共振也是没问题的
And she has no problems with MRI machines.
还有其它的应激诱因
There are other kinds of stress.
她听到你和你丈夫吵架了
She heard you and your husband fighting.
很不幸  她听过很多更糟的
Unfortunately, she's heard a lot worse than that before.
不是这个原因
It's not stress.
也可能是继发性雷诺综合征
Could be secondary raynaud's.
系统性红斑狼疮可以解释艾米丽的症状
Lupus is consistent with emily's symptoms.
她的淋巴结不大
Her lymph nodes aren't enlarged.
而且她没有免疫激活征象
And she has shown no signs of immune activation.
也可能是重金属中毒
It could be heavy metal poisoning.
哪来的毒  旋转木马吗
From what? The carousel?
她不过坐了一小会儿
She was only on it for a minute.
三周前  西蒙搬进了一栋旧公寓
Simon moved into an old apartment building three weeks ago.
他肯定不清楚
I'm sure he has no idea
隔热层是什么做的
what the insulation's made of,
墙是什么漆刷的
what kind of paint.
他是个好父亲
He's a good father,
但对艾米丽的健康问题...
but when it comes to Emily's health...
我去拿钥匙
I'm gonna get his keys
看看他家的环境
and check for environmentals.
狼疮更说得通
Lupus is a better fit.
我不是故意想摆架子
I don't mean to pull rank here,
但我是她母亲
but I am her mother.
我记得你说  你是以医生的身份加入的
I thought you said you were here as a doctor.
作为医生  凡事都需要监护人同意
And as a doctor, I need parental consent.
这事我同意了
See above.
我去检查时
While I'm gone,
请为她进行螯合疗法
please start her on chelation therapy.
她是个母亲
She's the mother.
就把她当成个普通的母亲吧
So let's treat her like any other mother.
我想我们发现病人母亲的宝藏了
I think we just hit the environmental mother lode.
有意思  她怎么从没提起过
Funny she never mentioned an entire basement
这一地下室的危险化学品和药物
full of dangerous chemicals and drugs.
你说她会让艾米丽下来这里吗
You think she'd even let Emily down here?
会的
Yeah.
显然艾米丽经常来
Apparently a lot.
你听说过Lex-2这个药吗
You ever heard of Lex-2?
看到过介绍
Read about it.
是一种氨基糖苷类抗生素  还在实验阶段
It's an experimental aminoglycoside antibiotic.
号称可修复ATM基因的DNA错误
Supposedly it can override DNA errors in the ATM gene.
这不能说明她在给女儿用这个药吧
Doesn't mean she's giving it to her daughter.
每个研究AT的人  都会研究这种药物
Anyone studying A-T would be researching it.
怎么个研究法
How?
你看见有小白鼠吗
You see any lab rats down here?
这里唯一的牢笼就是那个
The only cage I see is right there.
走开
Go away.
我头疼
I have a headache.
我们也不是非要搞基
We don't have to have sex.
搂搂抱抱  说说话就足够了
Sometimes it's nice just to cuddle and talk.
我先说吧
Me first.
你根本不需要再听别人的意见
You don't want a second opinion.
你已经问了五个人了
You're already on your fifth.
你问过仁爱医院的埃文斯  县医院的肖
You got Evans at Mercy, Shaw at County,
约翰·霍普金斯的福斯特
Foster at Johns Hopkins.
他们给出的建议是一致的
And every one of them has given you the same advice.
你疯了
You're nuts.
你不仅仅想要做化疗
You don't just want chemo.
你想要加大剂量
You want a dose so high,
大到致死的可能性有三分之一
there's a one-in-three chance it'll kill you outright.
问题是
Question is,
你为什么没和我说
why didn't you tell me?
因为你知道我会阻止你
Because you knew I'd stop you.
也就是说你已经找到一个
Which means you've already found someone
足够疯狂
insane enough
或足够绝望的人
or desperate enough
来给你注射致命剂量的药物
to give you what amounts to a death dose of chemicals.
但是谁会这么傻呢
But who would be that stupid?
据我猜测  那人就是你
I'm thinking that the who is you.
你到底准备
Where exactly were you planning
在哪里自杀
on killing yourself?
我认为福曼是不会让你死在医院里的
'Cause I don't think Foreman is gonna let you do it here.
在我家里
My place.
我已经准备了不少设备  不要
I've been stockpiling equipment. No.
不要  住手
No! Stop.
我现在还算健康
I'm still healthy.
现在尝试极端的方法
Why not go the extreme route now
还能有较大的存活几率
when there's a better chance of surviving it?
从统计数字上来看
Statistically,
对你来说  使用这个疗法
this treatment has about the same chance
与胸腺瘤的死亡率是相同的
of killing you as the thymoma does.
但是这样会死得更快
But a hell of a lot faster.
这是南希·威尔斯的遗物
Nancy Wells,
她患的是宫颈癌
cervical cancer,
有百分之七十的存活率
70% survival rate.
死于1998年11月6日
Died November 6, 1998,
享年六十四岁
64 years old.
伯尼·琼斯  黑色素瘤
Bernie Jones, melanoma,
百分之八十九的存活率
89% survival rate.
死于1999年10月10日
October 10, 1999.
死时五十二岁
He was 52.
约翰·泰勒
John Taylor.
甲状腺癌
Thyroid.
有百分之九十六的存活率
96% survival rate.
我向他保证过他会没事的
I promised him he'd be fine.
他去世时才八岁
Eight years old.
我不愿意躺在病床上
I am not going to die slowly
在惨白的日光灯下  慢慢等死
in a hospital bed under fluorescent lighting
不愿意人们驻足在我床前
with people stopping by to gawk
编着谎说我气色不错
and lie about how I look.
哪怕有那么一丝可能
Even a small chance of that happening
都是我接受不了的
is too big a chance for me.
你个白痴
You're an idiot.
我打赌你肯定没命
And the odds say you're gonna die.
来我家给你治疗
We'll do it at my place.
我们认为  唯一能导致你女儿病症的
The only environmental factors we think
环境因素就是
caused your daughter's illness
你给她注射的药物
are the ones you shot her full of.
我负责试验药物
I tested the drug.
我干这行  已经有十年了
This is what I did for a living for ten years.
她是你女儿  不是实验用的豚鼠
She's your child, not a guinea pig.
给她用之前我试验过
I tested it first.
在我自己身上
On myself.
用药六个月中  我没有发现
And in six months, I didn't document
任何的不良反应
any adverse effects.
仅仅一例临床试验说明不了问题
A trial of one is basically irrelevant.
AT病人出现呼吸道感染很常见
Respiratory infections are common with A-T.
而对艾米丽的这种基因变异
With emily's mutation,
呼吸道感染是致命的
they are deadly,
而且病情每年都在恶化
and they get worse every year.
Lex-2至少要有五年才会被批准
Lex-2 won't be approved for at least the next five years.
反观艾米丽
Emily, on the other hand,
可能活不过这个冬天
wouldn't have survived the winter.
我该怎么办呢
What was I supposed to do?
新药需通过药监局的认可  这是有原因的
There's a reason for FDA requirements.
杰克逊纪念医院的研究...
A study at Jackson Memorial--
我知道盖恩斯的研究
I know about Gaines' research.
他打算下个月发表
He's publishing next month.
不会发表了  我刚和他通过电话
Was. I just spoke to him.
他的团队在Lex-2实验鼠上
His team just linked the use of Lex-2
发现了肾衰竭的症状
to renal failure in mice and rats.
她需要B超引导下肾穿刺活检
She needs an ultrasound guided renal biopsy
来检查肾脏损伤情况
to check the damage.
希望损伤是可逆的
Hopefully it's reversible.
为了你的愚蠢
To stupidity.
我还没说完
Mm, not quite done.
为了即将到来的肌痛  肌痉挛
To muscle aches, spasms.
以及那种蚀骨般的
To your joints feeling like they're being ripped out
掏心之痛
and replaced with shards of broken glass.
我是否应该记录下来
Should I be writing any of this down?
胆汁将充满你的胃
Your stomach fills with bile.
你呕吐时  感觉就好似有人
When you vomit, it feels like someone's forcing
将烧得发红的锤子硬塞下你的食道
a white hot hammer down your esophagus,
撕扯你的食管
tearing your flesh.
鲜血顺着喉咙流下
Blood's dripping down the back of your throat,
让你哽咽窒息
choking and gagging you
同时  你会尝到一种油腻腻的铜臭味
with the slick, coppery taste of burnt pennies.
我是肿瘤科医生  我明白--
I am an oncologist. I know--
如果你真明白
If you did,
我们也不会在这里坐着了
we wouldn't be sitting here.
第二天  你的白细胞没了
Day two, your white blood cells are gone,
身体将暴露在各种攻击之下
opening up your system to attack.
体温直线上升
Your temperature skyrockets.
前一秒钟  你的皮肤热得像火烧
One second, your skin feels like it's on fire.
瞬间  又冷得像是掉进了冰窟窿
The next second, it's entombed in ice.
身上每个痛觉感受器
Every pain sensor in your body
都在同一时间被激发了
is firing at the same time
疼到痛苦不只是一个词或一个概念
until agony isn't even a word or a concept
而是你唯一的现实
it's your only reality.
你开始产生幻觉
You hallucinate.
你梦见死亡
You dream of death.
此刻  生存死亡的竞赛开始了
And then the race begins.
你的身体能否在有机生物和寄生虫
Can your body claw its way back in time
夺得你的生命之前
before the hostile organisms and parasites
恢复健康呢
claim you permanently?
赢了  你就活  输了  你就死
Win, you live. Lose, you die.
威尔森  我们准备怎么做呢
Now what are we doing here, Wilson?
1号肾脏看起来不错
Kidney number one looks good.
估计得从2号肾脏取活检了
Which means we'll probably take the biopsy from two.
表现很不错
Hey, you're doing great.
像往常一样勇敢
Brave as always.
挺酷的吧
Pretty cool, eh?
你想试试吗
You want to try?
怎么了
What's wrong?
我的胸口很痛
My chest hurts.
绝对不是肾出问题
It's definitely not her kidneys.
没事的
It's okay.
放心吧  这个吐出来和吃下去时
Promise this'll taste just as good coming up
味道一样好
as it did going down.
万一出什么差错
If things go wrong,
你要知道
I just want you to know--
如果你只是想说你一直对我暗怀基情
If you're gonna say that you've always been secretly gay for me,
大家其实早就知道了
everyone always just kind of assumed it.
你要知道
I just want you to know...
我很感激你愿意冒这个风险
that I appreciate the risk you're taking...
在你的客厅里给活人注射
pumping a human being full of lethal chemicals
致命的化学药品
in your living room.
要是我死了  你那位监督官那儿
If I die, it probably won't go over well
肯定很难摆平
with your probation officer.
不会有事的
That's not gonna be an issue.
我很欣慰  至少你挺自信的
I'm glad at least one of us is confident.
我可没有
Not me.
真要是搞砸了
I've already identified
我早已物色了几处
a couple of spots to dump your body
弃尸的好地方
if this goes south.
我挺喜欢三一公园的
I've always enjoyed Trinity Park.
那里离湖边倒是挺近的
It does have a nice access to the lake.
肌肉痉挛已经开始了吗
Muscle spasms already?
不  这不算什么
No. It's nothing really.
这是好消息
Good news.
大多数人需要两袋
Takes most people two bags
才会到这个阶段
to get to that stage.
你已经大大领先了
You're way ahead of schedule.
你会觉得我的想法很蠢
You'll think it's stupid.
那你还不是照样我行我素
That hasn't stopped you before.
我一直以为
I just always thought,
哪一天我老了病了
when I got old or sick,
会有妻儿陪伴在旁照顾
I'd have a wife or kids to look after me.
这个场景中
And in this scenario,
你亲爱的妻儿
are your loving wife and kids
是握着你生命维持系统的电源呢
holding the life support cord,
还是在打量着你的遗嘱
or are they thumbing through your will?
我也在场的吧
I'm in it, right?
你需要的东西都在这里了
You have everything you need right here.
我也是
We both do.
止痛药
Painkiller.
工业力量  [游戏《红色警戒》的地图]
Industrial strength.
选择难度  天堂模式
Level...awesome.
我们在度假
We're on vacation.
还真舒服
That is nice.
她的肾没问题
Her kidneys are fine.
我认为这不是Lex-2
I don't think we're looking at side effects
产生的副作用
from the Lex-2.
她很容易发生呼吸道感染  肺炎吗
She's prone to respiratory infection. Pneumonia?
但她没有持续性咳嗽  寒战或者大量出汗
No persistent cough, chills, or excess sweating.
有没有可能是肺栓塞
What about a pulmonary embolism?
符合咯血的症状  但是血栓呢
Fits coughing up blood, but a clot?
是什么导致的呢
From what?
她从旋转木马上掉下来摔得淤青
Bruising from when she fell off the carousel.
挫伤了深静脉
Contusion damages a deep vein,
造成了血栓
causes a clot.
掉下来一小块  循环到了她的肺部
A piece breaks off, travels to her lungs.
我们需要给她用肝素
We need to get her on heparin now.
再来一个血栓就可能导致心肌梗塞了
Another embolism could cause a heart attack
或者脑梗塞
Or a stroke.
怎么了  艾米丽出事了吗
What's wrong? Is it Emily?
算是吧
Sort of.
你不能这样做
You can't do this.
我要带她去仁爱医院
I'm taking her to Mercy.
你们所做的一切只是让她越来越糟
Everything you people have done has just made her worse.
你没这权利  我们有共同监护权
You don't have the right. We have joint custody.
你把她当作实验鼠时
Where was my right when you were treating
怎么没想过我的权利
our daughter like a lab rat?
要不是我她早已死了
She'd be dead if I hadn't.
够了
Stop it.
你们女儿不应受到这种对待
Your daughter deserves better than this.
没事  亲爱的
It's okay, sweetie.
我和妈妈只是想谈谈
Mommy and I are just gonna talk.
好吗
Okay?
我们去吃糖好吗
You want to get some candy?
我们认为艾米丽的肺部有血栓
We believe Emily has a clot in her lungs.
要是你现在离开  在新医生
If you leave now, she could die
还没了解情况之前她可能就没命了
before her new doctors are even up to speed.
是AT引发的吗
From her A-T?
是从旋转木马上摔下来造成的
From the fall off the carousel.
我们能不能停止相互指责
Now can we just stop blaming each other
做出正确的选择呢
and do the right thing here?
你真觉得这能一样吗
You're really gonna equate the two?
不  你给了她几分钟的乐趣
No, you were giving her two minutes of fun.
我可是在挽救她的生命
I was trying to save her life.
她最好的朋友是谁
What's her best friend's name?
她最喜爱的老师是谁
What's the name of her favorite teacher?
为何她讨厌你给她的那个动物玩具
Why does she hate that stuffed animal you gave her?
近来她的噩梦中总有企鹅出现
She's been having nightmares about penguins all month.
她是什么血型
What's her blood type?
Rh因子呢  她的血清免疫球蛋白水平
Rh factor? Her serum immunoglobulin levels?
管他是什么  都只是数据和字母
I don't care. Those are letters and numbers.
-那不是她  -那么在她
- That's not her. What about the varient
E14/ATM基因间启动子区里的变体呢
in her E14/ATM intergenic promoter region?
这正是杀死我们女儿的元凶
Because that's what's killing your daughter.
除非我能找到重新激活的方法
Unless I can find a way to reactivate it.
只要让她好起来就行
Just make her better.
你看上去不怎么好  先生
You don't look too good, mister.
你怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
从门进来的
The door.
你是病了还是怎么了
Are you, like, sick or something?
豪斯人呢
Where's House?
你父母呢
Where are your parents?
我认识你  你住在这楼里对吗
Oh, I know you. You live in the building, right?
你叫什么
What's your name?
你不记得了吗
You don't remember?
豪斯
House.
你答应过我能回家的  威尔森医生
You promised me I'd go home again, Dr. Wilson.
你说过不是我的错
You said it wasn't my fault.
确实不是  约翰
It wasn't, John.
如果我没做错什么
If I didn't do nothing wrong,
为什么我会死
why did I die?
我不知道
I don't know.
听着
Look...
我不该这么做的
I shouldn't have done this.
我死了吗
Am I dead?
还没
Not yet.
只是感觉像死了一样
It just feels that way.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我的意思是  除了疼痛呕吐腹泻抽搐以外
I mean, apart from the pain, vomiting, diarrhea, and cramps?
我从医学院毕业后在实验室
I worked six months in a research lab
工作了六个月
after med school.
在那里你的精神会高度集中
You get so focused.
有一次我两天没吃东西
Once I didn't eat for two days.
那里很容易让你忘记什么才是最重要的
It's easy to forget what actually matters.
我没有
I didn't.
我给她买错玩具确实很糟但是...
Yeah, it sucks I got her the wrong doll, but...
好消息
Good news.
艾米丽的肺没问题
Emily's lungs are clear.
-没有凝块  -坏消息是
- No clot. - And bad news.
我们还是不知道她怎么了
We still don't know what's happening to her.
不论怎样都与肝脏有关
Whatever it is, there's liver involvement.
她的眼睛出现了黄疸
Her eyes are jaundiced.
她的肝脏正在衰竭
Her liver's failing.
我们在她的肝静脉中发现了梗阻
We found a blockage in her hepatic vein,
这限制了血液流向她的肝脏
which is restricting blood flow to her liver.
真性红细胞增多症
Polycythemia vera?
红细胞计数正常
Red blood counts are normal.
可能是某种结缔组织疾病
Could be some sort of connective tissue disorder.
如果说
What if--
如果我们只是看到了她病情发展的
What if we're just seeing the end result
最终结果呢
of her condition?
她是如此特殊
She's unique.
从我俩身上分别遗传了变异基因
One screwed-up gene from each of us.
我们还是按照流程来吧
Let's stick with our process.
我应该离场
I shouldn't be here.
我们遗漏了什么
What are we missing?
重症莱姆病
Advanced lyme disease.
那能在血液中发现
Would have seen it in the blood.
他说了重症
He said advanced.
我们没在她的血液中发现
We wouldn't pick it up in her blood
因为病菌可能已经转移到器官或神经系统里了
if it's in her organs and nervous system now.
除了流鼻血外这符合一切症状
It fits everything but the nosebleed.
但为什么现在发病呢  还是同时发病
But why is it attacking now, all at once?
是什么变了
What's changed?
是伊丽莎白
Elizabeth has.
她停止给艾米丽注射Lex-2
She stopped giving Emily the Lex-2.
那是一种氨基糖苷类抗生素
It's an aminoglycoside antibiotic.
这是莱姆症被抑制的原因
It's what was keeping the Lyme in check.
我们得开始给她用阿莫西林
We need to start her on amoxicillin.
你骗我
You lied.
这玩意儿吐出来的味道太差了
Doesn't taste better coming back up.
还有个谎话  你看上去不错
Here's another one. You look good.
白细胞计数到多少了
What's the white blood cell count?
1000以下了  还在下降
It's down to 1,000, still dropping.
我需要更多的吗啡
I need more morphine.
没有了
We're out.
过去八小时你都在用
You've been using my personal supply
我私人珍藏的止痛药
of painkillers for the last eight hours.
你有...你有足够我俩吃的吗
You have-- you have enough for both of us?
我这的储存量够一个祈祷班吃的呢
I've got enough stashed around here for a minyan.
记住这是给你的礼物
Just remember they're a gift.
如果你再继续吐就太不礼貌了
So it's rude to keep throwing them up.
我是在你给我的烛台旁找到的
Found that out with those candlesticks you got me.
我们认为是莱姆病
We think it's Lyme.
那我应该看到相应的症状
I would have seen signs of that.
如果Lex-2对其有抑制作用就不会
Not if the Lex-2 was keeping it in check.
我们生活在城里
We live in the city.
我们不养宠物
We don't have pets.
她也从没在森林里呆过
She's never even been in the woods.
我呆过
Yes, I have.
和爸爸一起
With daddy.
我早该告诉你
I should have told you,
不过我知道你会怎么想
but I know how you feel about it.
我从小跟我爸一起打猎
I grew up hunting with my dad.
我也想和我女儿分享这经历
I wanted to share it with my daughter
哪怕一次也好
at least once.
我们只是照了照片
We only took pictures.
你不用着急
You don't need to be mad.
也许我们该出去
Maybe we should step outside.
不用
No.
我们没法让她与世隔绝
We can't protect her from everything.
我估计你们需要做腰椎穿刺来确诊
I assume you'll need a lumbar puncture to confirm.
你的接触片掉了吗
You lost a contact?
我要去厕所
Going to the little boy's room.
那些叫做成人纸尿裤是有原因的
They're called adult diapers for a reason.
用吧
Use it.
我用了  如果你认为
I did, and if you think
我会让你改变我
I'm gonna let you change me--
没事的  我是个医生
It's Ok. I'm a doctor.
放开我
Just leave me alone.
太可悲了
It's pathetic.
我太悲剧了
I'm pathetic.
一个得了癌症的肿瘤学家
An oncologist with cancer.
世上那么多东西能杀了我...
Of all the things that could be killing me...
这就好像宇宙对我
It's like the universe is giving me
竖了个大大的中指
the big middle finger.
宇宙才不关心你呢...
The universe doesn't care--
为什么是我
Why me?
我经常对我的病人们说
I'm always telling my patients
不要折磨自己  因为没有答案
not to torture themselves, because there's no answer.
不错的建议
Sound advice.
残忍的忠告
It's cruel advice.
他们不过是在
They were just
为自己的遭遇找一个理由
trying to make sense of what was happening to them,
我却告诉他们别傻了
and I'm there telling them not to bother?
我应该像你那样生活
I should have spent my life being more like you.
做一个好摆布人  以自我为中心
Should have been a manipulative, self-centered,
自恋的混蛋
narcissistic ass
给身边所有人所有事带来痛苦
who brought misery to everything and everyone in his life.
你还是会得癌症
You'd still have cancer.
没错
Yeah!
可我会觉得自己罪有应得
But at least I'd feel like I deserved it.
你们说我爸爸妈妈会和好吗
Do you think my parents will get back together?
我不知道
I don't know.
我想他们一定是相爱的  可是...
I'm sure they love each other, but...
他们只是因为我才吵架
They only fight about me.
因为他们太爱你了
That's because they care so much.
所以说不定我死了以后
So maybe when I die,
他们可以重归于好
they'll get back together.
艾米丽  怎么了
Emily, what's wrong?
我的手臂不能动了
I can't move my arm.
抬着手臂别放下
Just keep your arms up for me.
她怎么了
What's happening to her?
她中风了
She's having a stroke.
够了  你的心率上升  血压下降
Okay, your heart rate's up, BP's tanking.
白细胞500
White blood count's at 500.
必须马上去医院
We have to go to the hospital now.
-不  -我这里没有急救设备
- No. - I don't have the equipment or the meds to handle this.
不  不胜则死
No. Win or lose.
不胜则死  我们说好的
Win or lose. That was the deal.
我答应你是因为有赢的可能
That was the deal when there was an "or".
你赢不了的
You can't win this.
不
No.
不  我宁愿死在这里
No. I'd rather die here.
不要死在急救车里
Not in an ambulance.
不要死在医院里
Not in a hospital.
求你
Please,
你不能那样对我
you can't do that to me.
我不能...
I can't...
豪斯
House...
求你
Please.
答应我你不会那样对我
Promise me that you won't do that to me.
答应我
Promise me.
好  我答应你
Okay, I promise.
中风
Stroke.
肝静脉梗阻
Blockage in her hepatic vein,
咯血
coughing blood,
呼吸困难
trouble breathing,
雷诺氏现象
and Raynaud's.
如果不是已经排除了可能
If we hadn't already ruled it out,
听起来倒像肺栓塞
it sounds like textbook pulmonary embolism.
什么像血栓又不是血栓
What mimics a clot but isn't a clot?
真菌感染
Fungal infection.
她的脑脊液是干净的
Her CSF was clean.
没有细菌或真菌感染标志
No bacterial or fungal markers.
有谁给豪斯打过电话
Anyone tried calling House?
他不接电话
Not picking up.
也不回信息
Or returning messages or texts.
我们得靠自己了  说说有用的理论
We're on our own here, so just give me some theories we can use.
恶性血液病
Hematologic malignancies.
AT病人更易患那种类型的癌症
A-T patients are more prone to that form of cancer.
你认为癌症可能三天内显现症状并且致命
You think cancer would present and kill her in three days?
不是癌症
Not cancer.
而是表现像血栓的肿瘤
But a tumor could act like a clot.
心房粘液瘤
An atrial myxoma.
一种原发性心脏肿瘤
A primary heart tumor.
粘液瘤的摆动
The swinging motion of the myxoma
间歇性地阻断右心房的血流
intermittently blocked the flow of blood through the right atrium.
流入通道的梗阻阻止了肝静脉的回流
Inflow blockage stagnated the hepatic vein,
导致血栓  进而导致肝衰竭
which clotted and caused liver failure.
而流出通道的梗阻导致了雷诺氏现象和脑梗塞
Outflow blockage caused the Raynaud's phenomenon and stroke.
肿瘤脱落的碎块卡在了肺里
pieces of the tumor broke off and lodged in the lungs,
导致艾米丽呼吸困难和咯血
causing Emily's breathing problems and the coughing blood.
我们会手术切除肿瘤
We'll remove the tumor surgically,
希望活检能够显示它是良性的
and hopefully the biopsy reveals it's benign.
你...
You...
你造型真是衰透了
You really look like crap.
正在与感冒作斗争
Been fighting a cold lately.
等上七到十天  肿胀消退
Seven to ten days for the swelling to go down.
然后再去扫描  安排手术
Then we rescan and schedule the surgery.
我好像记得
I seem to recall
我对你说了一些话
I said some things to you...
你说了很多话
You talked a lot.
讲到你害怕海豚之后我就没再听了
I stopped listening after you confessed your fear of dolphins.
可以先把基友情意放一放吗
Can we just tone down the bromance a few notches?
我的腿疼死了
My leg is killing me.
再帮最后一个忙
One last favor.
我好歹想自己去上次卫生间
I'd like to actually make it to the bathroom this time.
你不是说存了很多维科丁吗
I thought you said you had plenty of vicodin.
人都会说谎
Everybody lies.
这么说我经历的痛苦  你大部分时候
So the way I felt, you feel that, what,
都身处其中
most of the time?
你活得也够惨的  是不是啊
It really does suck being you, doesn't it?
至少我没得癌症
At least I don't have cancer.
肿瘤是良性的
The tumor was benign.
我们已经把它全部摘除了
And we were able to remove all of it.
是不是我以后就不生病了
Does this mean I'm not sick anymore?
不  亲爱的
No, honey.
你的基因问题不是肿瘤造成的
The tumor didn't cause your genetic condition.
你的病还没好
You're still sick.
生病也阻挡不了我们  是吧
But we never let that stop us before, right?
出院以后你想去做什么
So what do you want to do when we get out of here?
去过水族馆吗
Have you been to the aquarium?
很赞的
It's pretty cool.
我们能去吗  爸爸
Can we go, daddy?
当然
You bet.
我能吗
Me too?
她能跟我们一起去吗
Can she come with us?
妈妈去不需要问的
You know mommy never has to ask.
午饭见
I'll see you at lunch.